ANDREI ALEXANDRU TALPAN

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/andrei-alexandru-talpan Github: github.com/deiu80

Profile

Computer Science graduate from University of Essex with working experience in industry. My strong organizational skills, eagerness to embrace new challenges, and commitment to excellence set me apart. I am confident in my ability to perform at the highest standards and thrive in fast-paced environments.

Education

University of Essex, BSc (Hons), Computer Science (Placement Year)

Sept 2019 - July 2023

Bachelor of Science with Honours Class I

Degree mark: 81

Colegiul National de Informatica (National College of Computer Science)

Sept 2015 - June 2019

Romanian Baccalaureate - Computer Science (8.40), Maths (9.75), Romanian Literature (8.60)

Overall: 9.00 (marks out of 10) equivalent with AAA

Work experience

Amazon – Software Development Engineer Intern

June 2023 - September 2023

- Improved a process for internal customers ensuring data delivery to external customers within legal timeframe.
- Solution was build using AWS Step Functions, SQS, Lambda and S3

Amazon – Software Development Engineer Intern

July 2022 – October 2022

- Full stack project-based internship regarding internal resource management that resulted in 50-60% reduction in operational effort for the team
- Acquired a solid understanding of microservice architecture, including distributed systems and the principles
 of RESTful API design.
- Utilized a wide range of AWS services such as API Gateway, DynamoDB, Lambda, IAM, CloudWatch, CloudFront
- Built a key component of an internal portal using Angular and TypeScript
- Conducted automated testing using TestNG, ensuring high-quality software delivery, and carried out the DevOps process using agile methodologies
- Documented the solution and presented it to the entire division's stakeholders, demonstrating strong communication and ownership skills.

Egress Software Technologies – IT Operations placement

July 2021 – July 2022

- Provided IT support to internal users across all departments to ensure smooth business operations
- Performed susceptibility scans and managed the resolution of threats for internal endpoints
- Documented, developed and implemented cloud strategies to better organize the IT infrastructure in Azure
- Managed and audited user access control to all internal apps and systems
- Troubleshooted hardware/software faults and deployed updates to applications
- Followed security protocols and liaised with internal stakeholders to grant access to sensitive customer data platforms

Skills

Organisation & Time Management

• Developed ability to multi-task and prioritise workload according to business needs

Organized my workload according to manager's needs and urgent requests during my time at Egress.

Problem Solving:

- troubleshooting various hardware/software errors and patching security vulnerabilities
- developed and tested my solution using a range of AWS services and various programming languages

Flexibility & Adaptability:

- Successfully adapted to a new work environment while working in the cybersecurity and in corporate division at Amazon
- Very flexible regarding work schedule and able to prioritize tasks

Teamwork:

- As a software engineer, I have actively participated in design reviews, scrum retrospectives and code reviews
- As part of the IT department, I had to collaborate with multiple stakeholders across the business to resolve existent problems and improve operational processes

Languages: Romanian - Native, English - Proficient

Personal achievements

Received good feedback from manager, mentor and tech lead while interning at Amazon

Obtained recognition by management and peers of my contribution to the organization while at Egress

Distinction awarded and included on the Dean's List for Excellence in the first and second year.

References

Available on request